[{"Id":"1","Question":"Q.In internal fragmentation, memory is internal to a partition and :\r\n","OptionA":"a) is being used\r\n","OptionB":"b) is not being used\r\n","OptionC":"c) is always used\r\n","OptionD":"d) none of the mentioned\r\n","Answer":"Answer: b\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"2","Question":"Q.A solution to the problem of external fragmentation is :\r\n","OptionA":"a) compaction\r\n","OptionB":"b) larger memory space\r\n","OptionC":"c) smaller memory space\r\n","OptionD":"d) none of the mentioned\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"3","Question":"Q.Another solution to the problem of external fragmentation problem is to :\r\n","OptionA":"a) permit the logical address space of a process to be noncontiguous\r\n","OptionB":"b) permit smaller processes to be allocated memory at last\r\n","OptionC":"c) permit larger processes to be allocated memory at last\r\n","OptionD":"d) all of the mentioned\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"4","Question":"Q.If relocation is static and is done at assembly or load time, compaction _________\r\n","OptionA":"a) cannot be done\r\n","OptionB":"b) must be done\r\n","OptionC":"c) must not be done\r\n","OptionD":"d) can be done\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"5","Question":"Q.he disadvantage of moving all process to one end of memory and all holes to the other direction, producing one large hole of available memory is :\r\n","OptionA":"a) the cost incurred\r\n","OptionB":"b) the memory used\r\n","OptionC":"c) the CPU used\r\n","OptionD":"d) all of the mentioned\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"6","Question":"Q.CPU fetches the instruction from memory according to the value of\r\n","OptionA":"a) program counter\r\n","OptionB":"b) status register\r\n","OptionC":"c) instruction register\r\n","OptionD":"d) program status word\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"7","Question":"Q.A memory buffer used to accommodate a speed differential is called\r\n","OptionA":"a) stack pointer\r\n","OptionB":"b) cache\r\n","OptionC":"c) accumulator\r\n","OptionD":"d) disk buffer\r\n","Answer":"Answer: b\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"8","Question":"Q.Which one of the following is the address generated by CPU?\r\n","OptionA":"a) physical address\r\n","OptionB":"b) absolute address\r\n","OptionC":"c) logical address\r\n","OptionD":"d) none of the mentioned\r\n","Answer":"Answer: c\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"9","Question":"Q.Run time mapping from virtual to physical address is done by\r\n","OptionA":"a) Memory management unit\r\n","OptionB":"b) CPU\r\n","OptionC":"c) PCI\r\n","OptionD":"d) None of the mentioned\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: None."},{"Id":"10","Question":"Q.For real time operating systems, interrupt latency should be\r\n","OptionA":"a) minimal\r\n","OptionB":"b) maximum\r\n","OptionC":"c) zero\r\n","OptionD":"d) dependent on the scheduling\r\n","Answer":"Answer: a\r\nExplanation: Interrupt latency is the time duration between the generation of interrupt and execution of its service."}]